<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Buey</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/</link><description>Recent content on Buey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</managingEditor><webMaster>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 01:56:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.buey.net.br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Desinformação na Era da Informação</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/a-desinformacao-na-era-da-informacao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 01:56:20 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/a-desinformacao-na-era-da-informacao/</guid><description>Trabalho acadêmico apresentado em cumprimento das exigências da disciplina de Ambiente Profissional e de Extensão (APEX II) do Curso Superior de Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas.
Orientador: Carla Reis
São José dos Campos 2024
##RESUMO
Este trabalho visa delinear a situação atual do problema da desinformação e das fake news nas redes sociais. Para tanto, foi realizada uma pesquisa bibliográfica sobre os diversos pressupostos de análise do problema e as abordagens mais recentes para sua minimização.</description></item><item><title>Today I learned: Django</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/today-i-learned-django/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:57:20 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/today-i-learned-django/</guid><description>Create a project $ django-admin startproject name_of_the_project Create an app inside the project $ python manage.py startapp name_of_the_app Remember that a project can have many apps inside.
Basic workflow Create a view # &amp;lt;app&amp;gt;/views.py from django.http import HttpResponse def index(request): return HttpResponse(&amp;#34;The view&amp;#34;) Create the URLs Wire the views in /urls.py by creating (for example) path() calls;
# &amp;lt;app&amp;gt;/urls.py from django.urls import path from . import views urlpatterns = [ path(&amp;#34;january&amp;#34;, views.</description></item><item><title>Proteção Excessiva</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/protecao-excessiva/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:53:20 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/protecao-excessiva/</guid><description>A diferença entre o remédio e o veneno está na dose. Não é assim que dizem?
Esta postagem é um desabafo. Há algum tempo que venho tendo problemas com sistemas de controle de autorização (OAuth), embora não tenha certeza se esses problemas sejam específicos do protocolo.
Dia desses eu tentei criar logins em diversos sites de emprego (pois é, na busca). Para criar esses logins eu utilizei minha autorização de acesso do e-mail que utilizo para todas as tarefas relativas a este site.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding Burglar</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/rebuilding-burglar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 21:17:20 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/rebuilding-burglar/</guid><description>I had the idea of making Burglar sometime in 2018. It would be a match-3 style game, but with a twist. The stones wouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow a rectangular grid, but a circular one. In a way, it&amp;rsquo;s something like four binary trees arranged in a circle. The stones appear randomly in one of the four central slots. Then, you have to decide if you move the grid clockwise or counter-clockwise. Choice made, the stone will migrate to the immediate outer circle in the direction of your choosing, and another one will surge in the center (in one of the four central slots and of random color).</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 09:20:26 -0300</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/projects/</guid><description>NSEW Virtual Keyboard NSEW is a virtual keyboard designed for text insertion with the directional keys of a remote controller (up, right, down, left and enter) or a numpad. The normal keyboard layout (a retangular box) is clumsy when used with this kind of device or in these specific conditions.
NSEW solves this situation minimizing the number of strokes needed to select a specific character, in accordance with the common letter frequency of the selected language (English is the default).</description></item><item><title>Interesting cast issue in Java</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/interesting-cast-issue-java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 22:53:19 -0300</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/interesting-cast-issue-java/</guid><description>Some days ago I was convinced by my friend Fernando to start learning Java. I wondered, &amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;rdquo;. While examining the first chapters of Java - A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide, I stumbled upon this interesting &amp;ldquo;issue&amp;rdquo;.
Because of Java&amp;rsquo;s automatic type promotion in expressions, an aparently correct code can cause compilation errors. See&amp;hellip;
byte b = 20; b = b * 2; // This will trigger a compilation error. You can&amp;#39;t assign an int to a byte.</description></item><item><title>Never in straight lines</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/never-straight-lines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 22:10:02 -0300</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/never-straight-lines/</guid><description>Today I ordered a pizza. I took the car and went to the restaurant to grab the order, instead of waiting for the delivery guy. It&amp;rsquo;s something I do from time to time. I payed for the pizza and walked to the car to get back home.
Then, this guy approached me, a total stranger. He had an unusual request to make. He asked me to give him a ride, so he could try to catch a bus somewhere else (the restaurant is located in a neighborhood not well served by bus lines).</description></item><item><title>I need a programming project idea</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/programming-project-idea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 09:56:02 -0300</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/programming-project-idea/</guid><description>The most common question I read in every thread, and I imagine you already have too, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m new at programming and I want to practice, can someone give me some project ideas?&amp;rdquo;.
Usually people have a very long list of responses right under the sleeve, and the options range from programming challenges to traditional and easy to build programs like a pomodoro timer, or a reminder. There are even complete projects devoted to this situation, some of them very interesting (and I&amp;rsquo;ll list them at the end of this post), but I want to share a different approach.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 09:20:26 -0300</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/about/</guid><description>Buey is my brainchild. I&amp;rsquo;m Alexandre Paloschi Horta, an aspiring developer. I program in Python, and I&amp;rsquo;m also getting my feet wet in Javascript. Besides that, I&amp;rsquo;m member of the Doom/Death Metal band Macacos da Manchúria, and I also write short stories, but they&amp;rsquo;re in my native language (portuguese), so no place for them in here. Last, and most important of all, I&amp;rsquo;m the husband of my dearest Thays and proud father of Bárbara (my beloved pepper jello) and Lavínia (my beloved star in the skies, someday we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.buey.net.br/nsew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/nsew/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Buey - NSEW Virtual Keyboard NSEW Virtual Keyboard Instructions Use 8, 6, 2 and 4 (up, right, down, left) keys to change the active key. Press 5 (enter) to select it. The selected character will be written to the form and the cursor will return to the central key (Mode). Select the central key (Mode) to change the keyboard mode (lowercase, uppercase, symbols, numbers). Back to projects.</description></item><item><title>A Ética Digital Nas Empresas</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/a-etica-digital-nas-empresas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>buey.horta@proton.me (Alexandre Paloschi)</author><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/a-etica-digital-nas-empresas/</guid><description>Trabalho acadêmico apresentado em cumprimento das exigências da disciplina de Ambiente Profissional e de Extensão (APEX I) do Curso Superior de Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas.
Orientador: Carla Reis
São José dos Campos 2023
RESUMO Este trabalho visa traçar um panorama sobre a ética digital nas empresas, sua gênese, suas características e as dificuldades de sua aquilatação. Para tanto, foi realizada uma pesquisa bibliográfica sobre as diversas perspectivas históricas do termo ‘ética’, e sobre diversos episódios atuais em que, nos diversos aspectos influenciados pela escalada tecnológica que presenciamos, a conduta empresarial passou ao largo do que se aceita como comportamento ético.</description></item></channel></rss>