<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Buey</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Buey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 22:10:02 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.buey.net.br/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never in straight lines</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/never-straight-lines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 22:10:02 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/never-straight-lines/</guid><description>Today I ordered a pizza. I took the car and went to the restaurant to grab the order, instead of waiting for the delivery guy. It&amp;rsquo;s something I do from time to time. I payed for the pizza and walked to the car to get back home.
Then, this guy approached me, a total stranger. He had an unusual request to make. He asked me to give him a ride, so he could try to catch a bus somewhere else (the restaurant is located in a neighborhood not well served by bus lines).</description></item><item><title>I need a programming project idea</title><link>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/programming-project-idea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 09:56:02 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.buey.net.br/posts/programming-project-idea/</guid><description>The most common question I read in every thread, and I imagine you already have too, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m new at programming and I want to practice, can someone give me some project ideas?&amp;rdquo;.
Usually people have a very long list of responses right under the sleeve, and the options range from programming challenges to traditional and easy to build programs like a pomodoro timer, or a reminder. There are even complete projects devoted to this situation, some of them very interesting (and I&amp;rsquo;ll list them at the end of this post), but I want to share a different approach.</description></item></channel></rss>